Charlie Street

7 Cassiobury Road, Weymouth, Dorset. DT4 7JN 07917601977 charlie.street1@btinternet.com

As a highly driven individual with a strong academic record, I throw myself into any challenge I am confronted with. With extra-curricular experience working in teams, I believe I can add value to any team-based project.

Education

- University (2014-2018) Studying MSci Computer Science at the University of Birmingham.
 - Achieved an average grade of 94% in first year with marks $\geq 94\%$ in 6 modules.
 - Won Best in Degree Programme 2014/15.
 - Won BCS Prize for Best in Year 2014/15.
 - Awarded School of Computer Science Excellence Scholarship during first year.
 - Studying optional modules of Computational Vision, Computer Security and C/C++.
- A Level (2012-2014) Studied at the Thomas Hardye Sixth Form, Dorchester.
 - Achieved an A* in A Level Maths, Physics and Computing. I also achieved an A grade in AS Further Maths and Chemistry.
- GCSE Level (2007-2012) Studied at the Wey Valley School, Weymouth.
 - Achieved 9 GCSE's, 1 at A* grade, 1 at Distinction grade, 6 at A grade and 1 at B grade.

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

- Java I have a strong level of proficiency, having used Java for multiple projects in the past year.
- Haskell Although I'm still learning this language, I already have a reasonable knowledge of it.
- **OCaml** I have an understanding of the syntax and underlying concepts of the language.
- Python I have familiarity in using this language, as well as the Tkinter library for GUI's.
- JavaScript I possess basic knowledge of the language to add functionality to web-pages.

Web Technologies

• HTML, CSS, XML I have enough knowledge of these to build basic, functional web-pages.

Other

- (Postgre)SQL I have the competency to define database entities and then query them.
- Git I have experience using git, having used it for any significant projects I have partaken in.
- LaTeX I have enough knowledge to produce clear and well formatted documents.
- Matlab I have a very simple understanding in utilising matrices and writing basic functions.

Employment

• Animal (clothing shop) I worked as a sales assistant in the Dorchester Store from November 2013 - September 2014, December 2014 - January 2015 and July 2015 - September 2015. Working in retail has given me experience working within a fairly small team of people as well as enhancing my communication skills, particularly when dealing with members of the public.

Extra-Curricular Interests And Experiences/Employment

- Duke Of Edinburgh Award Over recent years I have completed all 3 levels of the Duke of Edinburgh award scheme. This has required large amounts of team-work and communication, particularly during expeditions, which involved working in a team of 4 for 4 days on Dartmoor. This has also greatly benefited my leadership skills. I also partook in voluntary work including working in a local charity shop and aiding restoration work along a canal near Gloucester.
- Teaching a lesson at my sixth form During summer 2015 I was contacted by an old computing teacher to give a lesson to the current A2 students to aid their upcoming projects. I gave the lesson in September 2015 and chose to talk about the basics of Object Oriented Programming, followed by a tutorial on using the Tkinter library in Python. This gave me a great chance to learn how to communicate my ideas effectively.
- Music I am an avid musician, having played the guitar since I was 12 and having interest in multiple genres of music. This has required great commitment and perseverance. Additionally, for the past year, I have been a member of a rock covers band, providing lead guitar and backing vocals. Being an active member of a band has improved my ability to cooperate well within a group and to listen to those around me.
- Cooking Alongside my GCSE education, I also took a vocational NVQ course at my local college, giving me experience working in a functioning kitchen as well as working front of house in the college restaurant, both serving the public on a regular basis. Even after finishing the course, I still get enjoyment from it at home.

Additional Information

• BCS I am currently a student member of the British Computer Society.

References

Professor Peter Tino: P.Tino@cs.bham.ac.uk University of Birmingham, Birmingham, West Midlands. B15 2TT. (+44) (0)121 414 8558 Dr. Mark Lee: m.g.lee@cs.bham.ac.uk University of Birmingham, Birmingham, West Midlands, B15 2TT. (+44) (0)121 414 4765